<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Block Attack - Rise of the Blocks</title>
    <description>Block Attack - Rise of the Blocks is a puzzle/blockfall game inspired by Tetris Attack (Panel de Pon in Japan) for the SNES. The game is pretty action packed for a puzzle game :-)
</description>
    <link>https://blockattack.net/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://blockattack.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 20:06:28 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 20:06:28 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Version 2.5.0 released</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Version 2.5.0 has been released! Read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/blockattack/blockattack-game/v2.5.X/ReleaseNotes-2.5.0.txt&quot;&gt;release note&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/download/&quot;&gt;download it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;News this time includes widescreen support. Not that it makes much value, at the game uses a vertical playing field. However in fullscreen you no longer get the black bars in the side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previous versions did also suffer for a bug that meant that files was always loaded in reverse order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is now also possible to run in permanent software renderer mode for people who have trouble with the hardware accelerated 2d.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://blockattack.net/2019/05/25/version_2_5_0_released.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blockattack.net/2019/05/25/version_2_5_0_released.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A video from 2.4.0</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The previous video of the gameplay is almost 10 years old. It was time for a new one. So I have recorded a video of a VS game from the just released version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still 4:3 format like the game. I am planning to do something about that in the next version and then I may create a new video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xHxnGB2y_lg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://blockattack.net/2019/03/20/a_video_from_2_4_0.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blockattack.net/2019/03/20/a_video_from_2_4_0.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>video</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Version 2.4.0 released</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Version 2.4.0 has been released! Read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/blockattack/blockattack-game/v2.4.X/ReleaseNotes-2.4.0.txt&quot;&gt;release note&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/download/&quot;&gt;download it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game now offers several starting speeds for endless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SDL has been upgraded to 2.0.9 for the Windows version which brings some improvements to the window scaling.
The Windows version also has significantly improved unicode support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was going to create a trailer but video editing is still a skill I need to work on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://blockattack.net/2019/03/10/version_2_4_0_released.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blockattack.net/2019/03/10/version_2_4_0_released.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Version 2.3.0 released</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Version 2.3.0 has been released! Read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/blockattack/blockattack-game/v2.3.X/ReleaseNotes-2.3.0.txt&quot;&gt;release note&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/download/&quot;&gt;download it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game now remember the window size when running in windowed mode&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game controller has also been improved with and more strings are translatable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://blockattack.net/2018/07/01/version_2_3_0_released.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blockattack.net/2018/07/01/version_2_3_0_released.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Version 2.2.0 released</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Version 2.2.0 has been released! Read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/blockattack/blockattack-game/v2.2.X/ReleaseNotes-2.2.0.txt&quot;&gt;release note&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/download/&quot;&gt;download it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This version introduces a new font system that makes scaling and resolution handling a lot better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Windows users with HighDPI displays the game now works “out of the box”.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://blockattack.net/2018/05/20/version_2_2_0_released.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blockattack.net/2018/05/20/version_2_2_0_released.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Work in progress: New font handling</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The fonts in the current version does have some trouble. Some people find them hard to read, they scale really badly and they are completely broken on Windows High DPI displays.
I have been working a new font handling method for Block Attack. It is committed, merged to master and will be included in the 2.2.0 release that I hope to get ready before the end of May.
Until then I have a couple of screen shots:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/2018_04_04_fonts/blockattack_menu_font.png&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;image-2018-04-05&quot; data-title=&quot;Menu with new font&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2018_04_04_fonts/blockattack_menu_font.thumb.png&quot; alt=&quot;Menu with new font&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/2018_04_04_fonts/blockattack_2.2.0-snapshot-font.png&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;image-2018-04-05&quot; data-title=&quot;Game with new font&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2018_04_04_fonts/blockattack_2.2.0-snapshot-font.thumb.png&quot; alt=&quot;Game with new font&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://blockattack.net/2018/04/05/work_in_progress__new_font_handling.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blockattack.net/2018/04/05/work_in_progress__new_font_handling.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Linux build updated again</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It is not that long ago that I updated the precompiled Linux build to be using SDL 2.0.6 instead of 2.0.5. Now I have another update. The compiled Linux build is now compiled on Ubuntu 12.04. This was a bit harder as Ubuntu 12.04 has reached end-of-life. However it was necessary as Ubuntu 14.04 is semi broken. At least the ubuntu:14.04 Docker image is broken. libsdl2-dev has been broken in 14.04 for months now. Even though I compiled my own version of SDL2 the build turned out to not work properly on other systems. Most notably the fullscreen support was broken. Well, that is now in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://blockattack.net/2017/10/28/linux_build_updated_again.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blockattack.net/2017/10/28/linux_build_updated_again.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Linux build updated</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have updated the standalone Lunux build to use SDL 2.0.6 instead of SDL 2.0.5. SDL 2.0.5 apparently has a problem with keyboard input that resulted in some keys being recorded double. This seems to only affect Ubuntu. I have updated the standalone package. While the new one has working keyboard support it appears that there still are some problem with the fullscreen support. It is weird as the version compiled against the distributions version of SDL2 works perfectly. I guess creating a standalone version is just problematic that way… still want to figure it out though.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://blockattack.net/2017/10/15/linux_build_updated.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blockattack.net/2017/10/15/linux_build_updated.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Block Attack on itch.io</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the “old days” when you wanted to install a program then you downloaded it and installed it. Today that is not often the case. There are a large number of shops and download managers that takes care of most of the work. From a users point of view it is very convenient. So far I have not had Block Attack on any such platform. Most platforms are not geared towards independent developers or it was too cumbersome to setup. A couple of weeks ago I used the itch guide to create a standalone Linux version so the next step was logical: Add it to itch. I have now done so. I have tested it with the itch.io app and it works on both Linux and Windows. I’ll not stop distributing standalone copies but I believe you should have another option. Check it out &lt;a href=&quot;https://sago008.itch.io/blockattack&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://blockattack.net/2017/09/16/block_attack_on_itch.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blockattack.net/2017/09/16/block_attack_on_itch.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Linux build added</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;While I develop and run the game almost exclusively on Linux I have not provided a precompiled version so far. That has changed now. After having experimented with Docker and reading the &lt;a href=&quot;https://itch.io/docs/itch/integrating/platforms/linux.html&quot;&gt;itch.io package guide&lt;/a&gt;. I have now decided to try to provide a precompiled Linux version. I have tested it on old versions of Ubuntu, Debian and Fedora but not versions that have reached end-of-life. I have skipped out on CentOS. While the source is still the safest option this should give an easier alternative.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://blockattack.net/2017/09/03/linux_build_added.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blockattack.net/2017/09/03/linux_build_added.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
